立法會主席。
發現。
石禮謙議員就政府賬目委員會第六十一號報告書向本會發言，石禮謙議員。
Thank you, Mr President. On behalf of the Public Accounts Committee, I have the honour to table our report number 61 today.
The committee has, as in the past, decided to hold hearings on those chapters covered by the director's audit report number 61, which, in our views, contain more serious allegations of irregularities or shortcomings.
委員會的報告表今天，覆蓋我們的結論和建議，關於三個選出的十章節。
我 now report the conclusions and recommendations of the three chapters covered in our report number 61.
第一，我會講到直接土地撥款給私人會所。
以nil或 nominal premium，which are commonly called private recreation leases (PRLs)。
The committee found it unacceptable and inexcusable that the Home Affairs Bureau only started to conduct a comprehensive review of the PRL policy in September 2013, despite the fact that the Executive Council was informed by the administration.
在1969，，政府應該審視私人 recreational lease政策，從時至時，以確保公共利益。
continue to be served.
The administration was further urged by some members of the Legislative Council as early as 2002 to review the PRL policy.
委員會notes that the comprehensive review of the PRL policy would not cover the renewal of the remaining 13 PRLs that expire in 2011 or 2012, but might impact on the renewal of the PRL that expired after 2014.
preliminary results of the review are expected to be available by the end of 2014. To better monitor the implementation of the opening up scheme to provide eligible oxide bodies greater access to the club's facilities, under the renewed PRLs.
委員會敦促內政事務局盡快，a，擬定詳細指引，以幫助私人俱樂部。
Report the scheme usage in their quarterly reports, and B, set up a proper mechanism to verify the reported usage of the club sports facility by eligible outside bodies.
In order to ensure the proper and effective use of the PRL sites, the committee also urges the Home Affairs Bureau and the Lands Department to a, clearly define the scope and responsibility between them in conducting inspections of PRL sites and to formally.
A. on how such inspection should be conducted on a routine basis, and B. draw a set of assessment guidelines to ensure that only a reasonable proportion of the land on the PRL sites will be used for social and ancillary facilities. Mr. President.
我 like to declare my interest. I'm a member of a number of those clubs that have been mentioned above, and this was reported in the PAC meetings and in the report.
第二個主題，我將簡要報告的是管理山腳跳台。
委員會表達震驚和強烈不滿，並認為不可接受，雖然相關行業協會和相關政府部門普遍支持引入許可制度來規管和促進跳板運作。
七。
要address the various problems caused by the roadside skips.
The proposed permit system was eventually not taken forward.
地政部門考慮到placing of the roadside skips a road management issue, while the transport department consider it as a land issue. Unfortunately, such shuffling of responsibility have relegated the management of the roadside skips as a non-issue.
at the expense of public safety.
委員會認為，運輸部門應擔當先鋒，引入一個許可制度來規管和促進跳車行動，因為路邊跳車會造成阻塞和對路用户的安全威脅，這屬於運輸政策範疇。
Transport and Housing Bureau and the Transport Department to ensure smooth vehicular traffic and road safety.
行政已經向委員會建議，聯合工作小組將會成立，並有發展局、環境局及交通及房屋局等部門參與，以討論有關路邊截水槽的問題應如何處理。
委員會表達了極度的擔憂和強烈的不滿，並認為完全不可接受有關不悔改態度的態度，即交通及住房局逃避責任，指派交通部門擔任引導導入永久系統的領頭羊。
規管和促進跳繩操作，我繼續重申，出現於跳繩操作的問題是多方面的。
Thirdly, I shall turn to the committee's concern about allocation and the utilisation of public rental housing flats. The committee expresses great dissatisfaction and finds it unacceptable that the administration does not disclose information on the.
平均waiting time between the date of receipt of
Accepted application for public rental housing and the date the application was housed. As such information is very useful for the applicants in making informed decisions on whether to accept housing offer right away or wait for the next chance.
As there were over 110,000 applicants on the waiting list under the quota and point system.
And the time gap between registration and the housing offer could be as long.
在超過五年的時間，委員會表達了極大的不滿，並認為不當的是，行政部門沒有採取任何措施來篩選不符合資格的申請人從等待名單上。
因應長等待名單。
And the increasing average waiting time for public rental housing in recent years, the committee urges the administration to critically review the effectiveness of the better-off tenants policies in inducing better-off tenants to surrender their flats.
Mr. President, lastly, I wish to record my appreciation.
of the contribution made by members of the committee.
Our gratitude also goes to the witnesses who attended the hearings during the committee, helped by the committee.
Would also, I would also like to express our gratitude to the director of audit and his colleague for their unfailing report. Last but not the least, I express my appreciation for the electoral secretariat to the PAC. Thank you.
唔好食啦。
識幾多？
致謝議案，梁君彥議員會動議呢一項議案，馮檢基議員、單頌嘉議員、何